It's off!
Full already.
[Carja guard]
My duty is to guard, I don't get involved in politics.
She didn't even hesitate, she stood between the assassin and our Sun-King.
[Carja noble]
My family might still be alive and you're going to stand here and do nothing?
[Carja guard]
We've lost a dozen patrols beyond the valley. Our orders are clear, no more.
Freeholds were warned.
[Carja noble]
You're talking about orders. I'm talking about lives!
[Carja guard]
That's what the orders are for, to save lives.
Good day, citizen.
[Carja guard]
Sun bless you for saving the Sun-King.
[Carja merchant]
Don't pass up these goods!
Come take a look. I'll give you a good price.
[Carja merchants]
- Buy what you need, leave the rest.
- Look at these wares!
[Carja merchants]
- Buy what you need, leave the rest.
- Won't find better wares!
[Carja merchants]
- Check out these goods.
- You'll regret not stopping when you're in the thick of it.
- I've got all the best goods here.
[Carja merchants]
- You'll like what I have for sale, I promise.
- Don't pass up these goods.
[Carja merchants]
- Fine goods for a fair price.
- Check out these wares.
[Carja merchant]
You'll regret not stopping when you're in the thick of it.
[Carja merchants]
- Come take a look.
- You won't find better wares.
[Carja merchant]
Fine goods for a fair price.
Won't cost you a shard just to look.
[Carja merchant]
Only the finest goods here.
[Carja outlander]
Dervahl stormed the Palace and still he lives?
I bet those traitorous Oseram will just conveniently move…
[Oseram worker]
I wasn't sure about the Sundom at first, but it's growing on me.
[Fernund]
Oh, no!
[Fernund, thumping on locked door]
Let me in, by fire and spit, let me in!
Oh Fernund, our deal is off.
Oh it's you.
How about a new deal?
You could just cut off my finger, or my hand, or my left arm.
But that's my final offer.
Oh, it won't be enough.
You wouldn't.
Not here, not in front of everyone?
No one's gonna lift a finger to stop me.
You just led a group of men to their deaths, remember?
They were bad men.
I did a service really.
You did.
You did the service.
I'll make sure it never happens again.
I'll hold you to it.
Understood. You won't hear from any of us ever again.
I'd better not.
[Carja guard]
It's her, the hero!
He's guilty, he should pay!
[Carja guard]
There are no shadows under the noonday sun…
Just stay out of their way for now.
Now they're hunting me.
[whistle]
Maker's End, not much farther now.
Olin said he found an image of the woman I resemble on an ancient device.
If she's my mother, why would there be traces of her
all the way out here, so far from Nora land?
I don't get it. Who is she?
[voice from Focus]
Her name is Elisabet Sobeck.
[Aloy]
You! Spying through my Focus again?
Well, go on, what do you know about her?
[voice from Focus]
Stay on your present course and before long
you'll know her as well as I do. Maybe better.
[voice from Focus]
But be wary.
Maker's End is crawling with Eclipse troops.
[voice from Focus]
To help you deal with them, I've left some useful equipment just outside the ruins.
Your Focus will show the location.
Who is he and how does he know these things?
He said "Elisabet Sobeck".
What kind of name is that?
[Nora Brave]
So many dead. We'll all be dead, soon enough.
I saw some of the places you'd been.
The new settlers have no appreciation of craft.
They'd already piled your work in a ditch.
But I knew the signs to look for.
The scrabble in the dirt, those surprised splashes.
I did tell you we'd meet again.
Nil, still hunting bandits?
Oh yes.
I've been sharpening my blade, anticipating the scent of the fight.
Don't get me wrong, these scum are odorous.
A little panic and desperation really sets it off though, like an incense.
So what's your knife called?
Why would someone name a knife?
So much for small talk.
Are you ready?
I didn't need your aid before, and I still don't.
Now that I've seen what you can do, you don't get another camp for free.
Think of this as a friendly competition.
Huh, "friendly"?
[Bandit]
Right here, you …
Calm.
Ah, better. No more time to recover.
Need to keep my kit dry.
They're still looking for me.
[Bandit]
She's up on high.
Where'd you go?
[Bandit]
We're dead too if you don't fight.
Don't move, I got… ugh!
[Carja villager]
We're letting the Oseram decide what to do with him?
But he tried to kill our Sun-King!
[Carja guard]
The Oseram that tried to kill our Sun-King? Traitors, the whole tribe of them.
Alright.
[Carja guard]
We will never be able to repay you for the life of our Sun-King.
[Carja villager]
I'll wager Erend is behind Dervahl's extradition.
Oseram stick together, after all.
[Carja villager]
How did he get so close to the Sun-King?
The Oseram guard will be blaming their shadows for their mistakes.
No space.
[Carja villager]
Dervahl tried to kill the Sun-King, unbelievable!
Remember how the blood pounded in your ears?
They'll ring later, in the calm.
It's a call to arms from your inner desires.
Or a cry for help.
I wouldn't fight it.
So you used to be a soldier.
You fought for the Carja?
For them, against them, an empire always finds its wars.
You can't be picky.
The new king Avad saw things differently.
Called an investigation into war crimes.
Aren't all wars a crime to someone?
Still, I raised my hand and volunteered.
You volunteered to investigate?
No, I volunteered my confession.
No sense wasting time with an investigation.
You know of those places, lonely places, where people once were?
Now just a hole cut in the world.
Chances are I was there before.
What were these things you did, Nil?
Acceptable things under the circumstances.
Huh, acceptable to who?
I don't make decisions.
Let's just say the rules of engagement suited me.
But rules are important, a structure, cage.
I was sent to Sunstone Rock for two years.
The trade was fair.
Is this some kind of Carja ritual?
Our new Sun-King is a believer in rehabilitation, as am I.
In the heat of a stone cell in the dark, I learned to focus on what was truly important to me.
Have you found a new partner yet?
I thought we were partners.
I have my own roads to follow, Nil.
And they seem to lead back to bandits.
That works for me, I'm not suggesting a Carja wedding.
I'm never lonely where there's killing to be done.
Time to move on.
A brief encounter for us, but the end for them.
They were squalid lives anyway.
[Carja guard]
You stopped that assassin. Walk in light for your bravery.
[Carja villager]
The Oseram that tried to kill our Sun-King? Traitors, the whole tribe of them.
…conveniently moved Dervahl in transport to Mainspring.